Christopher Hines

+49 152 2687 4263 | chrishinesabdn@gmail.com

SUMMARY

With over 5 years of industry experience in software design, development, testing, and deployment I am confident in producing and delivering quality products across a wide variety of markets.

I am a practical person with an aptitude for learning and developing new skills. I particularly enjoy participating in problem-solving based responsibilities, and thrive on applying such responsibilities in a team environment.

I consider myself to be a calm, approachable person that thrives while learning from others, however, being a self-motivated individual I often perform with minimal supervision while maintaining a high standard of work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer @ Skoove

October 2017 - January 2020

- Music application development role (ReactJS / React Native + Objective C).
- Heavily involved in frontend architecture design and the creation and deployment of A/B tests.
- Additional responsibilities included automated testing and managing continuous integration systems.
- Played a key role in contributing to an agile, lean development and release cycle.

Software Developer @ IMES International

July 2014 - September 2016

- Web (AngularJS / ASP.NET C#) and application (Java / Python) development role.
- Additional responsibilities included database management (SQL) and company IT infrastructure management.
- Involved in several software projects from design to delivery, in addition to several inherited projects.

In addition to my full-time experience I have also been involved in multiple short-term contract positions, and a number of personal projects pursued in my own time.

EDUCATION

2010 – 2014: University of Aberdeen BA (Hons) Computing Science

Modules included:

- Application Development
- Artificial Intelligence
- Operating Systems

- Computational Intelligence
- Human-computer Interaction
- Security

In my final year honours project I produced a system capable of using natural language to describe workflow schematics to human users. The development of this project involved research, surveys, meetings with subject matter experts, and software design and development.

SKILLS

- JavaScript / React / React Native / Angular
- Swift
- Python
- Java
- C# + Objective-C
- .NET frameworks

- SQL Server / MySQL / SQLite
- Unit testing frameworks
- Version-control systems
- Software deployment + support
- CI Systems (App Center / NeverCode)
- Agile development

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Graphic design

I have a self-taught understanding of graphical editing software such as Photoshop, GIMP, and Paint.NET. This has proven useful when designing and creating graphical assets and user interfaces for software. In my previous positions I was often recruited to help with graphical design tasks or photo editing.

Music technology

I spend some of my spare time tinkering with various audio technology and software as a hobby. This began when I initially started using Audacity to make personal mixes of my favourite music. After graduating I learnt how to use Ableton Live, and have more recently taken the time to understand different audio sources and codecs. I have also developed an understanding of transcoding and learnt how to use spectral analysis to compare releases for my music library.